Preliminary Inventoryof the Atanas Slavov papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Atanas Slavov papers
1975-1982
82041
Slavov, Atanas
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, relating to Bulgarian civilization and literature, and to dissident intellectuals in Bulgaria.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Bulgarian émigré author in the United States.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter, relating to Bulgarian civilization and literature, and to dissident intellectuals in Bulgaria.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Bulgarian literature.; Bulgarians--United States.; Dissenters--Bulgaria.; Bulgaria--Civilization.
Collection Contents
- Resume, 1980 (Folder 1)
- Publishing correspondence, 1978-1980 (Folder 1)
- Academic panels and work correspondence, 1978-1980 (Folder 1)
- The Thaw of Bulgarian Literature, corrected manuscript, 1980 (Folder 1)
- With the Precision of Baths, undated (Folder 2)
  - "Chapter 5: Playboys" typescript, undated (Folder 2)
  - "Chapter 3: Pensioners" typescript, undated (Folder 2)
  - "Atanas Slavov, Notes 1935-1976," New York October 1975-Washington D.C. August 1977 (Folder 2)
- "On the Eastern European Mind after 1952," handwritten and typescript draft denoted "1st draft, 1979" (Folder 2)
- Meridian correspondence, 1980-1982 (Folder 2)
- Poetry typescript, 1977 (Folder 2)
- "Bulgarian Ideologies" panel for American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies correspondence, 1980 (Folder 2)
- The Thaw of Bulgarian Literature correspondence, 1979 (Folder 2)
- Memoirs correspondence, 1976 (Folder 2)
- Poetry correspondence, 1977 (Folder 2)
- RFE/RL writings, 1979 (Folder 2)
- Poems 1968, published volume, 1980 (Folder 2)